<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<?DOCTYPE help SYSTEM "help.dtd"?>		
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="help.xsl"?>
<topics>
    <topic name="Getting started">
        <question>		
            <name>About the game</name>
            <answer>
            </answer>
        </question>
        <question>
            <name>Downloading software to the LEGO kit</name>
            <answer>
            </answer>
        </question>				
    </topic>
    
    <topic name="Pacman Game">
        <question>		
            <name>Goal of the game</name>
            <answer>
                The goal of Pacman is to eat all the points on the playing field, 
                whilst not getting caught by the ghosts. The game ends when all points have
                been eaten or you have.
            </answer>
        </question>
        <question>		
            <name>Starting a game</name>
            <answer>
                To start a new game either choose "New Game" or "Load Level" on the title screen.
                If you choose "Load Level" you will be prompted to select a level file to play.
                If you choose "New Game" the last played, or default level will be used.<br/>                       
                If the game is Online mode you'll be prompted to turn on all three robots
                and place them facing upwards as shown on the game screen.
                Once this is done the game will begin.
            </answer>
        </question>
        <question>		
            <name>Playing the game</name>
            <answer>
                The game controls are simple. You can move in four directions up, down, left or right.
                The default key configuration is mapped to the directional keys. 
                These keys can be also be assigned to a connected joypad or W,A,S and D.  
                While playing you can pause at any time by pressing the escape key.
                <br/>
                Once a game has been lost or won you will be asked to save the replay of your game.
                If saved the replay may be viewed anytime by choosing the "View Replay" option
                from the title screen. <br/>
                After opting saving the replay you will be prompted to type in your name, 
                so that it might be added to the high score list of the current level.                
                As with the replay this is optional. <br/>
                High scores can be shown be choosing the "View High Scores" option from the title screen.                
            </answer>
        </question>
        <question>		
            <name>Online and offline play</name>
            <answer>
                The game has two modes online and offline. When playing offline you
                only play on your computer. When playing online you use three LEGO robots to
                emulate the ghosts and Pacman's movement on the field.                            
            </answer>
        </question>                
        <question>		
            <name>Loading a level</name>
            <answer>
                To load a level choose the "Load Level" option on the title screen, you'll
                then be prompted to select the level you wish to load. Once selected
                the game will start.
            </answer>
        </question>
        <question>		
            <name>Changing input device</name>
            <answer>
                The input device, or key configuration can be changed on the options screen
                by scrolling down to the selected entity and then by pressing right or left.
                If any USB devices are connected they can be selected here as well.<br/>                            
                Should you wish to play against a friend you can also assign keys to ghosts.
            </answer>
        </question>
        <question>		
            <name>Changing skin</name>
            <answer>
                The skin used to render the game screen can be changed on the options screen
                by scrolling down to the "Skin" option and cycling through the available options
                using the left and right keys.<br/>
                Skins shouls be placed in a seperate sub directory in the skin directory.
                Skins must have all the needed tiles to be accepted by the program. Tilesize is
                determined by the base.png tile.
            </answer>
        </question>
    </topic>
    
    
    <topic name="Game Interface Overview">
        <question>
            <name>Title screen</name>
            <answer>
                <img src=".\pictures\titlescreen.png" width="640" height="480" alt="Game title screen" /><br />
                To navigate the title screen press up or down, and enter to select an option.
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <strong>New Game</strong><br />
                        Start a new game using the currently loaded or default level.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Load Level</strong><br />
                        Start a new game by loading a new level.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>View Replay</strong><br />
                        A replay is the entire collection of movements recorded during a game session.
                        As with a normal game, a replay can be played both online and offline. An online 
                        replay should only be played when the appropriate physical field is available.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>View High Scores</strong><br />
                        This option let's you view the high scores assigned to the currently loaded level.
                        The high scores are recorded for the ten best players.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Options</strong><br />
                        This option let's you view the options screen.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Quit</strong><br />
                        If you choose quit the credits will be shown, once done the program will
                        terminate. Should you wish to quit imediately press the escape key.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </answer>
        </question>	
        <question>
            <name>Game screen</name>
            <answer>
                <img src=".\pictures\gamescreen.png" width="640" height="480" alt="Game screen" /><br />
                The game screen shows the level, with entities, in the middle of the screen 
                and points obtained so far in the top right corner.
                If you wish to pause the execution of the game press space. Whilst
                the game is paused you can press Y to quit to the title screen.                
            </answer>
        </question>	
        <question>		
            <name>Option screen</name>
            <answer>
                <img src=".\pictures\optionscreen.png" width="640" height="480" alt="Game screen" /><br />
                The options on the option screen are traversed similarly to the title screen by the up and down directional keys.
                Options are changed by pressing the left and right directional keys. 
                On the buttom of the screen a description of the selected option is printed.<br />
                The configuration you chose is saved and carried over between sessions.
                There is no way to reset to default options while running the program. To reset to default settings
                delete the file "options.cfg".
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <img src=".\pictures\0_2_0.png" width="44" height="44" alt="Pacman"/><strong>Pacman - Key config</strong><br />
                        The keys assigned to Pacman is left, right, up and down by default. 
                        The keys can be changed by using the arrowkeys. Be advised that assigning the same keyset (not including AI) will result
                        in one entity not moving.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <img src=".\pictures\1_2_0.png" width="44" height="44" alt="Ghost 1"/><strong>Ghost 1 - Difficulty / Key config</strong><br />
                        Change the difficulty or assign keys to the first ghost. Difficulties are described below.                     
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <img src=".\pictures\2_2_0.png" width="44" height="44" alt="Ghost 2"/><strong>Ghost 2 - Difficulty / Key config</strong><br />
                        Change the difficulty or assign keys to the first ghost. Difficulties are described below.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Skin</strong><br />
                        Change the skin used to display the game with.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Game Speed</strong><br />
                        Changed the minimum time it takes to perform a move. When playing online
                        speed is also dependent on the rate of communication.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Sound</strong><br />
                        Choose between some annoying sound effects and mute.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Interface</strong><br />
                        Specify via what interface the tower used to communicate with the LEGO
                        robots is connected. Usually USB.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                
                <strong>Difficulty settings</strong><br/>
                There are three difficulty settings ranging from easy to hard.
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Easy</strong><br/>
                        An easy ghost just wanders around randomly, as though it was blind.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Normal</strong><br/>
                        The normal ghost will give chase if you're in sight, sometimes it will
                        change it's mind but will soon follow you again. If the ghost looses
                        sight of you it will continue in it's current direction if it can.
                    </li>                    
                    <li>
                        <strong>Hard</strong><br/>
                        This ghost is unbeatable, it will find you if there is way.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </answer>
        </question>
        <question>
            <name>Highscore screen</name>
            <answer>
                <img src=".\pictures\highscorescreen.png" width="640" height="480" alt="High Score screen" /><br />
                The high score screen shows a list of the ten best ranked players of the last played level.                
            </answer>
        </question>		
    </topic>
    
    
    <topic name="Level Editor">
        <question>		
            <name>About Level Editor</name>
            <answer>
                Level Editor is an application with which you can create or scan your own levels and then
                use them in your Pacman game. Levels can be created using mouse or scanned using a LEGO robot.
            </answer>
        </question>
        <question>
            <name>Creating a level</name>
            <answer>
                To create a level that is playable, you need to select the path brush button on the 
                toolbar or go to the brush menu and select it there. 
                Once selected left-click or drag the mouse over the tiles you wish to add nodes to. 
                If you've misplaced a node or wish to delete one, right-click it.
                If you wish to add nodes with a special points value, change the number in the points textbox, 
                and draw over the nodes you wish to change value for or the tiles you wish to add new nodes to. <br/>
                Once you've done drawing nodes select the Pacman or ghost brush to add these. 
                You can only add one Pacman and two ghosts. Ghosts and Pacman can be removed by right-clicking them. 
                Once you've done placing entities save the level in a file by clicking the save in the file menu.
            </answer>
        </question>	
        <question>
            <name>Scanning a level</name>
            <answer>
                To scan a level choose "Scan New Level" from the "File" menu.
                The scan dialog will be shown. Before pressing scan please turn the robot you wish
                to use on, calibrate it and place it on a node. Remember to specify which port and robot your are using.
                Press scan to begin.
                Should robot somehow miss a spot or drive off the track, simply press pause and wait for the robot to stop.
                Once the robot has stopped remove any faulty nodes on the canvas, and replace pacman if neccesary.
                Should you need to rescan any nodes, simply remove and readd them. Once done editing 
                reposition the robot, facing the same position ad shown on the screen, and press pause.
                The robot should start scanning again.                
            </answer>
        </question>					
    </topic>
    
    <topic name="Level Editor Interface Overview">
        <question>
            <name>Main window</name>
            <answer>
                <img src=".\pictures\leveleditor.png" width="720" height="480" alt="Level Editor main window"/>
            </answer>
        </question>				
        <question>
            <name>Toolbar</name>
            <answer>
                The toolbar is placed below the menu bar and holds buttons for commonly used functions.
                <ul>
                    <li><img src=".\pictures\brush.png" width="11" height="12" alt="Path brush"/> <strong>Path brush</strong><br />
                        The path brush is used to draw the nodes that the entities of the game traverse. 
                        When left-clicking on an empty tile a new node will be added with the amount of points specified in the points textbox. 
                        When placing a new node, links will be established to any nodes adjacent to it. 
                        It is currently not possible to remove or add connections seperately. 
                        When left-clicking on an already existing node the points held by the node will be changed to 
                        reflect the number of points specified in the points textbox. 
                        When right-clicking on a node it will be removed and all connections and links to it severed.
                        The path brush can also be selected be pressing <i>"CTRL + 1"</i> or going to <i>"Brush > Use Path Brush"</i>. 
                        The path brush is the default brush.
                    </li>				
                    <li>
                        <img src=".\pictures\pacman.png" width="10" height="12" alt="Pacman brush"/> <strong>Pacman brush</strong><br />
                        The Pacman brush is used to place Pacman's starting position on the playing field. You can only place one Pacman. 
                        To remove any enitity on the playing field right-click it. To add Pacman left click on a none occupied node.					
                        The Pacman brush can also be selected be pressing <i>"CTRL + 2"</i> or going to <i>"Brush > Use Pacman Brush"</i>.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <img src=".\pictures\ghosts.png" width="12" height="12" alt="Ghost brush"/> <strong>Ghost brush</strong><br />
                        The ghost brush is used to place ghost starting positions on the playing field. 
                        You can at maximum place two ghosts. To remove any enitity on the playing field right-click it. 
                        To place a ghost left click on a none occupied node.
                        The ghost brush can also be selected be pressing <i>"CTRL + 3"</i> or going to <i>"Brush > Use Ghost Brush"</i>.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <img src=".\pictures\grid.png" width="12" height="12" alt="Show / hide grid"/> <strong>Show / hide grid</strong><br />
                        When clicked a grid will be layed over the canvas, so that each node can be distinguished. 
                        When clicked again the grid will be hidden. 
                        The grid can also be shown by pressing <i>"CTRL + G"</i> or going to <i>"View > Show Grid"</i>.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <img src=".\pictures\points.png" width="13" height="12" alt="Show / hide points"/> <strong>Show / hide points</strong><br />
                        When clicked the points associated with every node will be shown on the canvas.
                        When clicked again points will be hidden. 
                        Points can also be shown by pressing <i>"CTRL + P"</i> or going to <i>"View > Show Points"</i>.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Points textbox</strong><br />
                        The number in the points box denotes how many points will be associated with each new node drawn or old node edited.
                        The number of points a node holds can be checked by moving the mouse over it, 
                        whilst checking the points label on the status bar.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </answer>
        </question>	
        <question>		
            <name>File Menu</name>
            <answer>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <strong>New level - CTRL + N</strong><br />
                        Clears canvas and let's you start creating a new level. 
                        If the current level you're working on has not been saved, 
                        you'll be asked if you'd like to save it before creating a new one.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Scan New level - CTRL + SHIFT + O</strong><br />
                        Scan new level opens the scan level dialog and let's you scan a physical level using a robot. 
                        If the current level you're working on has not been saved, 
                        you'll be asked if you'd like to save it before creating a new one.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Open... - CTRL + O</strong><br />
                        Let's you open a previously saved level. 
                        Any highscores associated with the level will be removed once it has been changed! 
                        If the current level you're working on has not been saved, 
                        you'll be asked if you'd like to save it before creating a new one.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Save - CTRL + S</strong><br />
                        Let's you save the level you're currently working on. 
                        If you have previously saved the level it will be saved to the file you last saved it to. 
                        If you havn't previously saved your level, you will be asked to choose a file to save to. 
                        When changing a level all high score data will be removed.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Save As... - CTRL + ALT + S</strong><br />
                        Let's you choose a file to save the level you're currently working on to. 
                        When changing a level all high score data will be removed.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Quit</strong><br />
                        Shuts down the program.                         
                        If the current level you're working on has not been saved, 
                        you'll be asked if you'd like to save it before creating a new one.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </answer>
        </question>
        <question>
            <name>Brush Menu</name>
            <answer>
                <ul>
                    <li><strong>Path brush - CTRL + 1</strong><br />
                        The path brush is used to draw the nodes that the entities of the game traverse. 
                        When left-clicking on an empty tile a new node will be added with the amount of points specified in the points textbox. 
                        When placing a new node, links will be established to any nodes adjacent to it. 
                        It is currently not possible to remove or add connections seperately. 
                        When left-clicking on an already existing node the points held by the node will be changed 
                        to reflect the number of points specified in the points textbox. 
                        When right-clicking on a node it will be removed and all connections and links to it severed.
                    </li>				
                    <li>
                        <strong>Pacman brush - CTRL + 2</strong><br />
                        The Pacman brush is used to place Pacman's starting position on the playing field. 
                        You can only place one Pacman. To remove any enitity on the playing field right-click it. 
                        To add pacman left click on a none occupied node.					
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Ghost brush - CTRL + 3</strong><br />
                        The ghost brush is used to place ghost starting positions on the playing field. 
                        You can at maximum place two ghosts. To remove any enitity on the playing field right-click it. 
                        To place a ghost left click on a none occupied node.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </answer>
        </question>	
        <question>
            <name>View Menu</name>
            <answer>
                <ul>					
                    <li>
                        <strong>Show Grid - CTRL + G</strong><br />
                        When clicked a grid will be layed over the canvas, so that each node can be distinguished. 
                        When clicked again the grid will be hidden. 
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Show Points - CTRL + P</strong><br />
                        When clicked the points associated with every node will be shown on the canvas.
                        When clicked again points will be hidden. 
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Show High Score List - CTRL + H</strong><br />
                        When clicked the hight score list associated with the current level is shown.
                        The high score list has only been added for debugging purposes, changes will not be saved.
                        Be warned that if you save, after having altered a level, the list will be reset for reasons of fairness.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </answer>
        </question>	
        <question>
            <name>Skin Menu</name>
            <answer>
                The skin menu is dynamically created based on the skins found in the skins folder.
                To change the skin to one of the skins in the menu either click it or press ALT + the number shown in the menu.                
                Changing skins in the level editor does not affect which skin will be used ingame.
                <ul>					
                    <li>
                        <strong>Open Skin - ALT + 3</strong><br />
                        Let's you select a directory containing a skin you wish to view your level with.                        
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </answer>
        </question>	
        <question>
            <name>Help Menu</name>
            <answer>
                <ul><li>
                        <strong>Open Skin - F1</strong><br />
                        Opens this help file.
                </li></ul>
            </answer>
        </question>				
        <question>
            <name>Scan dialog</name>
            <answer>
                <img src=".\pictures\scandialog.png" width="421" height="266" alt="Scan dialog"/><br />
                The scan dialog is used to initiate the scanning of a physical level using a LEGO robot. 
                The window consists of a log, port list, robot list, scan and a cancel button. 
                While scanning the already scanned parts of the level will be shown on the canvas.
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Port list</strong><br />
                        Used specify which port the tower used to communicate with the robot
                        is placed on.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Robot list</strong><br />
                        Used specify the ID of the robot you wish to scan with.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Scan button</strong><br />
                        The scan button will start the scanning of a physical level. 
                        Before you press the scan button you should make sure 
                        that you've turned on your LEGO robot, calibrated it, given it a ID
                        corresponding to the number you've selected on the robot list, and
                        placed the LEGO robot on the physical level. 
                    </li>                        
                    <li>
                        <strong>Pause button</strong><br />
                        The pause button will halt the scanning process temporarily. 
                        Any data returned by the robot once paused is in effect will be ignored.
                        Pause should primarily be used if the robot drives of the track or missreads a node.
                        Once paused you can remove any faulty nodes on the canvas and add any missed nodes.
                        If any nodes need rescanning simply remove and readd them.                        
                        If pacman needs to be reposition simply remove and replace him.
                        Before you press pause again ensure that the robot has stopped and been placed as shown on the canvas.                        
                    </li>                   
                    <li>
                        <strong>Cancel button</strong><br />
                        The cancel button will stop the scanning process. 
                        Once you've stopped scanning a level you cannot continue scanning,
                        if you try anyways the scanning process will start over.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Log</strong>
                        The log is the large text area in the middle of the scan dialog. 
                        Status messages will be shown here.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </answer>
        </question>	
    </topic>
    
    <topic name="Support">
        <question>
            <name>Known errors</name>
            <answer>
                <ul>
                    <li>When closing level editor, user is not prompted to save level.</li>
                    <li>When closing level editor, you are allowed to view a level using an incomplete skin.</li>
                </ul>			
            </answer>
        </question>
        <question>
            <name>List of planned improvements</name>
            <answer>
                <ul>
                    <li>In level editor placement and removal of single connections between nodes</li>			  
                </ul>			
            </answer>
        </question>
        <question>
            <name>Contact</name>
            <answer>
                If you have any further questions or error reports please contact one of our team members. The team currently has no website.
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Troels Hagman-Hansen</strong><br/>
                        E-mail: <a href="mailto:troelshh@hotmail.com">troelsh-h@stofanet.dk</a><br/><br/>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Christian Holm</strong><br/>
                        E-mail: <a href="mailto:chrholm.dk@gmail.com">chrholm.dk@gmail.com</a><br/><br/>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Lau Maack-Krommes</strong><br/>
                        E-mail: <a href="mailto:lmk@lmx.dk">lmk@lmx.dk</a><br/><br/>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <strong>Mikkel Brøndsholm Nielsen</strong><br/>
                        E-mail: <a href="mailto:mikkelnielsen@chicks.dk">mikkelnielsen@chicks.dk</a><br/><br/>
                    </li>
                    
                    <li>
                        <strong>Magnus Hemmer Pihl</strong><br/>
                        E-mail: <a href="mailto:magnus.pihl@gmail.com">magnus.pihl@gmail.com</a><br/><br/>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </answer>
        </question>
    </topic>
</topics>